Animation Number 1
ＤＯ ＮＯＴ！
ＤＯ ＮＯＴ ＬＩＴＴＥＲ！
NO ENTRY
DANGER
（暦(こよみ)）あ…
Don't look at me like that.
そんな目をするなよ
It doesn't suit such a pretty face.
美人が台なしだぜ
Come on, smile.
ほら ニッコリ笑ってごらん
お前には笑顔が
いちばん似合うんだよ
You look best when you're smiling.
Come on, at least say something before digging in.
ほれ
“いただきます”くらい言えよ
あれ？
Huh?
Uh...
えっと…
30th April
Wait. No way...
いや でもまさか…
She may be a shadow of her former self,
（暦）
成れの果てとはいえ
搾りかすとはいえ
but she's still a proud vampire.
それでも彼女は 誇り高き吸血鬼だ
That's what she is.
そんな彼女がだよ
ドーナツのほうに
気が向いているだなんて
There's no way she'd go for donuts instead...
そんなことがあるわけ…
Don't crush my dreams!
（暦）夢を壊すな！
Hey, you okay?
だっ 大丈夫か？
Oh, that's right.
（暦）
あっ そうだ
Donuts
Animation Number 52
Golden Chocolate
Animation Number 53
One bite
Animation Number 56
Two bites
Animation Number 57
Three bites
Animation Number 58
Finished in three bites
って おっと… お座り！
Whoa!
Sit!
Purple Scene
Animation Number "None"
French Cruller
Animation Number 67
Napkin
On ground
（暦）お手
Hand.
Uhh, eat then, I guess.
じゃあ その… 食べ…
Wait, I brought these for Oshino...
いや でも これって そもそも
忍野(おしの)に持ってきたもんだし
I can feel the pressure.
（暦）
圧力を感じる
Time passes
Animation Number 84
Well, what I was feeling right then may have been my guilt for her.
まあ 僕が今
押しつぶされそうなのは
罪悪感のほうでかもしれない
I'm the one who forced the little
vampire girl into such a life, after all.
この吸血鬼幼女が
こんな生活を強いられているのは
やっぱり僕の責任なのだから
She hadn't spoken a word since spring break.
春休み以来
ひと言もしゃべらない彼女
She used to smile so often, but an
irritated, sour face is all she puts on now.
あれだけ よく笑っていたくせに
今や 不機嫌そうな仏頂面を
浮かべるのみ
Considering all that she's done, all that she had been doing...
彼女がしたこと
彼女がしてきたことを思えば
当たり前の情けを 人間として
I know I shouldn't pity her like any human would.
当たり前の情けを
かけるべきではないのは
分かっているけれど
分かったよ
Fine, you can have them all.
全部 お前にやるさ
じゃあ ３回 回ってワンと言え
Spin around three times and say woof!
（暦）
ふん しゃべらないのは
やっぱり しゃべらないか
I guess she refuses to speak after all.
（暦）食べ…
Eat.
They're off the hook!
（旧キスショット）ぱないの〜
この輪っか状の食べ物
マジで まいう〜！
These ring-shaped things are seriously delicious.
It's a treasure box of rings packed full of sweetness!
まさに甘みの詰まった
指輪の宝石箱じゃ！
（暦）
うっ 今 しゃべったか お前！
Did you just talk?!
Oh, I was just hearing things.
（暦）
何だ 幻聴か
What are you doing, Araragi-kun?
（忍野）
何やってんだよ 阿良々木(あららぎ)君
Araragi-kun, don't bully the vampire too much.
阿良々木君 あんまり
吸血鬼ちゃんをいじめるなよ
It'll come back to bite you later.
そういう行いは 禍根を残すぜ
I wasn't bullying her.
（暦）いじめてなんかないって
It's been bothering me since spring break, but has her mental age also reverted to that of a child?
つうか 春休み以来
ずっと思ってたことなんだけど
こいつ 何だか
精神まで幼くなってないか？
What else did you expect, Araragi-kun?
（忍野）
ああ そりゃ
しかたのないことだよ 阿良々木君
This isn't limited to vampires.
吸血鬼に限った話じゃない
All aberrations spawn from human beliefs.
怪異(かいい)ってのは 言うなら
人間の信仰で出来ているからねえ
Human beliefs?
人間の信仰？
That's right.
そう 人間がそこにあると思うから
そこにあるもの
Aberrations exist because humans think they exist.
それが怪異だ
They look like how people around them perceive them.
怪異は周囲の認識どおりに現れる
They act like what people around them expect.
周囲の期待どおりに振る舞う
That's what they are.
そういうものだ
Here, we have this vampire girl.
さて そこで この吸血鬼ちゃんだ
You're the only one who is cognizant of her, Araragi-kun.
今 この吸血鬼を認識しているのは
阿良々木君 君だけだ
Well, technically this also applies to me and the Class Rep,
厳密に言えば
僕や委員長ちゃんもそうだけれど
but the one who influences her the most...
まあ それでも いちばん強く
吸血鬼ちゃんが影響を受けるのは
...is you, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木君からだ
It's true that I did see her as an 8-year-old child, but...
（暦）
確かに僕は こいつのことを
どっか８歳児として
見てしまっているところは
あるけどよ
（暦）
それでも この図が僕の期待どおり
ってことはないだろう？
This obviously isn't what I expected.
Children don't always grow up exactly how their parents want, right?
（忍野）
子供が親の期待どおりに育つとは
かぎらないだろう？
But expectations still have an effect.
それでも期待の影響は受けるさ
おおむね そんな感じだよ
That's the gist of it.
Parents' expectations...
親の期待…
Family influences...
（暦）
家庭の影響
I'm not gonna lecture you about being a good citizen,
（忍野）別に真人間になれなんて
説教くさいことを
言うつもりはないけれど
but you risk being a bad influence on her if you keep messing around like that.
あんまり ふざけてばかりいると
影響ならぬ悪影響を
与えてしまいかねない
It's already...
ただでさえ
（暦）
It's already bad enough that a proud vampire like her had to fall to the level of an innocent child.
ただでさえ あの誇り高き吸血鬼を
こんな あどけない子供に
おとしめておいて
How can being a bad influence on top of that help?
その上 悪影響まで与えて
どうするんだよ
そういうことだ
That's what he meant.
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
A change of subject, Araragi-kun.
さておき 阿良々木君
We only briefly mentioned her earlier, but how's the Class Rep doing?
最前 ちらっと
話題に上がったけれど
委員長ちゃんは元気かい？
Huh? Like how?
はあ？ どうって… 別に元気だよ
She's doing fine.
Really?
（忍野）本当に？
Hmm, I see.
ふん なるほど 言えないわけか
So you won't say.
Meaning...
…と するとだ
I'll take it that something bad enough
to avoid mentioning happened to her.
言えないようなことが
彼女の身に起こったと
考えるのが妥当かな
That's worrying.
それは心配だね
You don't need to worry.
（暦）
お前が
心配するようなことじゃねえよ
It's Hanekawa's problem.
羽川(はねかわ)の問題だ
余計な口出しはできない
I can't do anything about it.
And even if I could, only she can help herself.
何かあったとしても
それは あいつが
一人で助かるだけ…
It's the only way she can be saved.
でしか救われないんだろう？
Oh? Then I won't ask further.
（忍野）
ふ〜ん じゃあ 追及はしないよ
Let's try the reverse approach.
アプローチを逆にしよう
Tell me anything but what you can't tell me.
言えないこと以外のことを
教えておくれよ
There's gotta be something about the Class Rep that you can tell me, right?
委員長ちゃんのことを
何から何まで
話せないってわけでもないだろう？
Recollection
Animation Number 166
I'm not sure how well I managed,
（暦）
僕は うまくかどうかは
分からないけれど
but I told Oshino everything about what happened today minus what I wasn't allowed to say.
口止めされている部分を伏せて
忍野に今日の出来事を話した
Araragi  Tsukihi
Animation Number 168
Starting with my sister waking me up.
朝 妹に起こされたところから
Hanekawa  Tsubasa
Animation Number 170
My meeting with Hanekawa.
羽川と会って
Time passes
Animation Number 172
And what happened afterwards.
そして そのあと
Time passes
Will you help me
Animation Number 181
End Recollection
Animation Number 182
Araragi-kun, I hope I'm wrong, but...
（忍野）
阿良々木君 まさか それは…
That wasn't a silver cat with no tail, was it?
銀色の尾のない猫じゃ
なかっただろうね？
That's what he said.
Animation Number 218
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
Well done for lasting this long.
Animation Number 219
Thank you.
Now it gets serious.
Animation Number 219
Animation Number 220
The meddlecat.
障(さわ)り猫(ねこ)
Meddlecat
Animation Number 225
A mammal of the family Felidae in the order Carnivora.
食肉目ネコ科の哺乳類
I'm currently collecting stories
about the meddlecat in this town.
障り猫は
今 僕が この街において
収集している怪異譚(たん)の１つさ
Wait a second, Oshino.
（暦）いや ちょっと待て 忍野
The cat Hanekawa and I buried isn't an aberration.
僕と羽川が埋めてやった猫は
怪異とかじゃねえよ
It's just a typical...
そういうんじゃなくて
ありものとしての…
Yes. I'd agree.
（忍野）
そう そういうんじゃないだろうと
僕もそう思うよ
I would think so too.
Normally.
普通ならね
But the Class Rep isn't a normal person.
だけど 阿良々木君
委員長ちゃんは
普通じゃないだろう？
She's pretty dangerous.
あの子はマジでヤバいんだぜ
Something as unremarkable as
burying a cat run over by a car...
車にひかれた猫を
埋めてあげたなんていう
ささいでありふれた
言ってしまえば
You might call it an everyday heartwarming episode.
ハートウォーミングな
日常のエピソードさえ
But it could mean a major event of
enormous importance given her involvement.
彼女の手にかかれば
天地を揺るがす
大事件になりかねない
The fact that it's a cat makes it particularly bad.
取り立てて 猫はマズいだろう
That Class Rep is perfect for the meddlecat.
あの委員長ちゃんに
障り猫はドンピシャだ
Oshino, what should I do then?
（暦）
忍野 じゃあ 僕はどうしたらいい？
Let's make this efficient and split up.
（忍野）じゃあ 阿良々木君
ここは手っとり早く
二手に分かれようか？
I'll go dig up the white cat you guys buried.
僕は君たちが埋めたという
白い猫を掘り起こしに行くよ
つまり 僕は お前に
So I just need to tell you the location.
猫を埋めた場所を
教えればいいんだな？
Instead, I'll have you do something else of significant importance.
（忍野）
その代わり 阿良々木君には
別の重要な役割を担ってもらう
（暦）え？
（忍野）言ったろ？
Like I said, we're splitting up.
（忍野）
だから二手に分かれるんだよ
You're going to approach the Class Rep directly.
阿良々木君には 委員長ちゃんに
直接アプローチしてもらう
（暦）ちょ 直接って？
D-Directly?
You're going to go to her house.
今から委員長ちゃんの家を
訪ねるんだよ
You'll meet her directly, look at her face and in the eye, talk to her...
そして実際に会って
顔を見ながら
目を見ながら話をして
and confirm that she's safe.
彼女の無事を確認してくるんだ
A one-man search party
Geez, this has gotten messy.
やれやれ
何か大変なことになってきたな
つうか こんな時間に家を訪ねて
どうやって羽川に会うんだよ
And how am I supposed to show up and
meet her at this hour of the night anyway?
ＭＩＮＯＲＳ ＡＮＴＩＣＳ
Privilege of the underaged
III
II
I
Hanekawa?
羽川？
Huh? Wait...
あれ？ でも…
Is that really Hanekawa?
羽川なのか？
（障り猫）にゃおん
（障り猫）にゃん
にゃお〜ん
（暦）はっ 羽川？
H-Hanekawa?
（障り猫）にゃんだ お前
Who are you, meow?
ご主人の友達か
にゃんかにゃのか？
A friend of my myaster's, perhaps?
にゃっはは
Come to think of it, your face does look familiar.
そういえば見覚えがある気が
しねえでもねえにゃ
俺を埋めるときに
一緒にいたヤツか
You were with her when she buried me.
ふん じゃあ ちょうどいいにゃ
Perfect timing.
I don't get it at all, but aren't friends
supposed to help each other, meow?
俺にゃ 全然分からにゃいが
友達同士ってのは
助け合うもんにゃんだろ？
I'll leave these two with you, then.
つうわけで こいつらのこと
あとは任せるにゃ
ふん
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
What's the word again?
（障り猫）
えっと にゃんだっけにゃ
Oh right, they're apparently my myaster's "parents".
そうそう そいつらは
ご主人の両親ってヤツらしいぜ
ふん よく分かんにゃいけど
I'm nyot too sure, though.
Please get rid of them for me, friend.
友達！ お前が適当に
処分してやっといてくれ
にゃんにゃらお前が
Or if you'd like, meow...
You could finish them off.
殺してもいいぞ
おっ おい 待てよ 羽川！
H-Hey, wait!
Hanekawa!
"Wait", you say?
待て… とかよ
Don't you just thrust every kind of
expectation onto my myaster, damn it.
そうやって にゃんでもかんでも
ご主人に期待してんじゃねえよ
ボケが！
お前らが そんにゃんだから
You lot are the reason she's become like this!
ご主人が
こんにゃんにゃんだろうが！
（障り猫）ニャ〜！
（暦）あっ
（障り猫）ウニャ〜！
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
（暦）ぎゃああ〜！
痛(いって)え〜っ！
Ow!
Don't myake such a fuss over one arm.
（障り猫）
騒ぐにゃよ これくらいのことで
Compared to the pain my myaster has tolerated her entire life,
その程度の痛み
ご主人が
ずっと耐えてきた苦痛に比べれば
this is like getting bitten by a mosquito.
蚊に刺されたようにゃもんだろうが
Your... master?
“ご主人”ってのは…
Does she mean Hanekawa?
（暦）
羽川のことか？
That's right, humyan.
（障り猫）ああ そうだよ 人間
Myaster has me nyow.
ご主人には もう俺がいる
だからお前は いらにゃい
So she doesn't need you.
She doesn't need her parents, friends, or anyone.
両親も友達も誰も いらにゃい
She doesn't even need herself.
ご主人自身さえ
いらにゃい
Wh-What do you mean?
いっ いらないって
I'm setting my myaster free.
（障り猫）
俺が ご主人を
自由にしてやるんだよ
誰よりも自由ににゃ
Freer than anyone else.
I'm sure you know nyo one else can do that.
知っているだろう？
それはお前たちには
できにゃかったことだ
お前たちはご主人を縛るばかりで
不自由を与えるばかりじゃにゃいか
The lot of you just tie her down, robbing her of her freedom.
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
ふん まずは地球にも匹敵する
スケールのストレスから
Red Scene
Animation Number "None"
I'll start by releasing the stress within her that could myatch the Earth in scale.
解放してやるところから始めよう
（暦）うっ 羽川…
Hanekawa...
Hanekawa  Tsubasa
Animation Number 373
The girl with abnormal wings
Animation Number 374
Animation Number 387
On
The first thing I did after the meddlecat left was to deal with the messed up situation.
（暦）
障り猫が去ったあとの僕が
第一にしたことは
とっ散らかった状況の後始末である
I started by calling an ambulance.
まずは救急車の呼び出し
Under normal circumstances I'd need a deck brush and a lot of water to clean up
そして本来ならば 住宅街の道路に
血液で打ち水をしてしまったという
シチュエーションの処理には
the pool of blood I had left on the street,
大量の水とデッキブラシが
必要となってくるけれど
まかれた僕の血は
完全に蒸発しきっていた
but my blood was already evaporating away.
血液の蒸発などに
疑問を覚えることは もとよりない
I didn't even blink at the sight of it happening.
I had gotten very used to it during spring break.
春休みには見飽きた光景だ
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
In fact, I should have wondered why my blood
was taking much longer to evaporate than usual.
むしろ その血の蒸発に
やけに時間がかかった事実に対し
僕はここで疑問を覚えても
よかったはずなのに
Black Scene
Animation Number "None"
って うわ！ おっ…
（忍野）お目覚めかい 阿良々木君
You're awake, Araragi-kun?
You slept in quite a bit.
随分とお寝坊さんだねえ
待ちくたびれたよ
I was getting tired of waiting.
もう太陽も沈んじまうぜ
The sun's about to set.
え〜 僕 12時間以上
寝てたのか
30th April
I was asleep for over 12 hours?
I thought you were going to die for a while there.
（忍野）
そのまま
死んじゃうんじゃないかと思ったよ
フッ ハッハ〜
Oshino! Hanekawa is—
（暦）おい 忍野！ 羽川が…
（忍野）
ああ 分かってる 分かってる
もう聞いたって
Yeah, I know, I know.
I've already heard.
The Class Rep's become a cat, right?
委員長ちゃんが
猫になってたんだろう？
心配は的中したってわけだ
My suspicions were right on the mark.
吸血鬼ちゃん もういいぜ
You can go now, vampire.
What's going on, Oshino?
えっ どういうことだ 忍野
Why was she awake at this time of day?
大体 どうしてこんな時間に
あいつが起きてたんだよ？
Well, your wounds were pretty serious.
（忍野）
いやいや 阿良々木君のケガが
あまりにひどかったからね
I got her to help out a little.
吸血鬼ちゃんには
ちょいと協力してもらってたのさ
ほれ
You two are very strongly connected together.
君たちは つながりすぎるほどに
つながっているからさ
Your ability to regenerate is also coupled to hers,
回復力についても連動している
so the closer you are to each other, the stronger it gets.
従って 距離が近ければ近いほど
そのスキルは強度を増すのさ
（暦）は〜ん
You should thank her later.
（忍野）あとで お礼言っときなよ
（暦）
しかし 確かに意外じゃあったぜ
I'll admit I was caught off guard.
I'd just given her some blood, so I figured my
regenerative strength would be better than that.
あいつに
血を与えた直後だったからな
もっと回復力があるもんだと
思ってた
No, given how resistant to death you are now,
you should be able to handle fairly serious wounds.
（忍野）
いや 今の阿良々木君の
不死力ならば
相当の負傷にまで
耐えられるはずだ
You should be able to recover from nonfatal injuries instantly.
致命傷以外ならば
瞬時に回復するくらいだ
But in this case...
だけど この場合
...your opponent was bad.
相手が悪かった
I should say compatibility instead of opponent.
相手というか相性かな
Her compatibility was bad.
相性が悪かった
That meddlecat is no good.
障り猫はダメだ
N-No good?
だっ ダメって？
You were meddled with by the meddlecat.
（忍野）障り猫に障られた—
Meddle
Its touch deals no ordinary damage.
障られたがゆえの負傷は
ただのダメージじゃないからね
Touch
"Let sleeping cats lie."
触らぬ猫に たたりなしだ
えっと 阿良々木君
エナジードレインって分かるかな？
Hmm, Araragi-kun.
Do you know what "energy drain" is?
Energy drain?
エナジードレイン？
えっ でも エナジードレインって
むしろ吸血鬼の特性じゃないのか？
Wait, isn't that a characteristic of vampires?
Exactly.
（忍野）そのとおりだよ
だけど別に それが
吸血鬼の専売特許ってわけでもない
But that doesn't mean it's unique to vampires.
（暦）
はあ つまり僕は
左腕を引きちぎられると同時に
So she basically took away some of my resistance to death along with my left arm when she ripped it off.
不死力までも
引きちぎられていたってことか
You're done for if you let the meddlecat touch you.
障り猫には障られたら
それでアウトなんだ
（暦）それで“障り猫”か
So that's the meddlecat.
しかし
But an energy drain capable of suppressing vampire-tier resistance is quite formidable.
吸血鬼の不死力を圧倒するほどの
エナジードレインっていうのは
確かに脅威だな
Ah, no, no.
I guess I didn't explain it very well, Araragi-kun.
これは僕の言い方が悪かったな
阿良々木君
When I said her compatibility was bad,
I meant with regards to you.
相性が悪かったっていうのは
阿良々木君との相性って意味でさ
I wasn't saying meddlecats could
match vampires in terms of strength.
別に能力的に障り猫が吸血鬼に
匹敵するという意味じゃないよ
Vampires are the kings of aberrations, after all.
（忍野）
だって吸血鬼は 怪異の王なんだぜ
The king. The big shot.
王様 キングなんだぜ
They both have energy drain, but
they're on completely different levels.
同じエナジードレインとはいっても
ランクが違うさ
Meddlecats are small fry to vampires.
障り猫も吸血鬼にとっては
ただの雑魚だ
Small fry...
（暦）雑魚？
You may have given her your blood right before and be part-vampire, but beneath that you're still just a human.
（忍野）
阿良々木君は吸血鬼ちゃんに
血をあげた直後で
そりゃ いくらかは
吸血鬼化しているんだけれど
あくまでも人間
There's no way you can defeat a purebred aberration.
怪異そのものに勝てるわけがない
A purebred aberration...
（暦）怪異 そのもの…
I went and took a look at the cat's grave you told me about.
（忍野）
阿良々木君に教えてもらった
猫ちゃんのお墓を
軽く荒らしてみたけれどさ
There was nothing buried there.
何も埋まっていなかったよ
This is the worst possible case.
事態はおよそ最悪だね
I see.
（暦）そっか
とはいえ ケガの経過自体は
順調のようだね
That said, your injury is healing nicely.
The insides haven't fully reconnected yet, but at this rate you should be good by tomorrow.
まだ中身は
つながりきってないっぽいけれど
これなら明日には治ってるだろう
The vampire's probably sleeping by now, so thank her next time.
吸血鬼ちゃんは
もう寝てるだろうから
今度 お礼を言っときな
Well, it'd be trouble for her if you died, so it's
only natural that she stayed with you for the day.
まあ 彼女にとっても
阿良々木君に死なれたら
困るだろうから
ひと昼 付き添うくらいのことは
当然なんだけどね
それでも ありがたい話だよ
Still, I'm grateful.
The fact that she recognizes that she needs me for nutrients means she at least has the will to live on.
栄養源としての僕を
必要としてくれてるってことは
あいつが少なくとも
生きようとしてくれてる
ってことなんだからさ
（忍野）
ハア〜 そういう意味
じゃないんだけどねえ
That's not what I meant.
Dumbass.
朴念仁
Whatever.
（忍野）まあ いいや
You should go home before your family gets too worried.
じゃあ 阿良々木君
おうちの人が心配しないうちに
帰りなさい
The cellphone in your pocket
buzzed quite a number of times.
（忍野）
ポケットの中で携帯電話が
随分と振動していたみたいだけど
What's that called? Silent mode?
バイブ機能っていうんだっけ
そういうの？
Missed calls
146 Missed
Messages
209 Unread
They're probably all from Karen and Tsukihi.
（暦）
多分 全部 火憐(かれん)と月火(つきひ)からだ
Unlike the Class Rep, you have a family that cares about you.
（忍野）
委員長ちゃんと違って
心配してくれる家族がいるんだから
You should go home, Araragi-kun.
君はもう帰らなくっちゃね
阿良々木君
Stop it, Oshino.
やめてくれよ 忍野
こんなケガは何でもない
These wounds are nothing.
羽川があんなことになってるのに
すごすご帰れるはずがないだろう
How can I possibly plod home with Hanekawa in that state?
It has already begun.
既に状況は
開始されてしまっている
What remains is work for professionals.
ここから先はプロの仕事だ
There is no place for an amateur here, much less a schoolkid.
素人の まして未成年の
出張る幕じゃないんだよ
I keep a pleasant demeanor so it might not be obvious to you,
僕は このとおりのお調子者だから
そんなふうには
見えないだろうけどさ
but I feel bad about letting you sustain such a serious injury.
阿良々木君に そんなひどいケガを
させてしまったことを
悪いと思ってるんだぜ
I've failed as a balancer.
バランサー失格だよ
I ignored theory and went against policy.
僕はセオリーを無視して
ポリシーに反したことを
してしまった
The wounds you received this time are largely my responsibility.
君が今回受けた被害は
かなりの割合で僕の落ち度だ
I should apologize to your parents.
親御さんに申し訳ない
You've done more than enough already.
阿良々木君は ここまでで
十分に役割を果たしたんだ
Araragi Koyomi-kun.
阿良々木 暦君
There is nothing further that you can do.
ここから先
君にできることは何もない
君は委員長ちゃんのために
何もできない
There is nothing you can do for the Class Rep.
Even if you want to, you can't.
したくてもできない
It's not a question of your feelings.
気持ちの問題じゃない
It's a matter of your technique—your strength.
技術の 実力の問題だ
If anything, I'd say that staying out of my way is your most important task.
強いて言うなら
この僕の邪魔をしないことこそが
君の大切な仕事なのさ
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Here's your preview hallucination.
（旧キスショット）
予告幻聴じゃ
Zenmonogatari is now in Production!
We!
Are the Fire Sisters!
擬死(ぎし)という生体反応がある
Some beings have a reaction called "apparent death".
I will make all my wishes come true!
It uses the character for "imitation", not "fake".
偽(にせ)の死ではなく
擬(もど)きの死と書いて擬死じゃ
Basically, it means acting dead.
Oh! She's the cat from New Year's!
Catch her!
要(よう)は死んだフリじゃな
昆虫などが食われそうになったら
するらしい
Bugs and such do it when they're in mortal danger.
I have you trapped, fire sisters!
We're in a pitfall trap
つまり 人間が熊に会(お)うたら
死んだフリをするみたいなものか
In the end, it's similar to what humans do when a bear chases them.
Look on enviously as you sit powerlessly!
My last wish is to hijack the episode preview!
Wait, that's kind of a stupid thing to do.
いや それダメじゃろ
次回「つばさファミリー 其ノ參(そのさん)」
Next time. Tsubasa Family, Part 3.
Next Time
Tsubasa Family Part 3
Do it when an aberration is after you and death walks onto the stage.
She got it first!
怪異に会(お)うたら 死ぬ前フリじゃな